nm.org 2015-04-13

# Privacy Policy | Northwestern Medicine | (312) 926-2000

###  Website Privacy Policy 

Northwestern Memorial is committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to its Web site. It is our goal to maintain compliance with the highest standards of Web site privacy so our visitors may comfortably and safely use the site for a range of healthcare information needs. As used here, "Northwestern Memorial" means Northwestern Memorial Hospital and where appropriate, its affiliated and parent organizations.

###  Information Collected 

Our system routinely collects information about origin and site navigation of Web site visitors. This information is used only to help us continually modify the site based on use patterns and is not linked to any personal identifying information. We do not collect any identifying or personal data on site users unless that information is submitted as part of a request for service or information, such as requesting an appointment. Northwestern Memorial uses several "cookies." By using our Web site, you agree that we may place these and other similar types of cookies on your device and access them when you visit the Web site in the future.

A "cookie" is a small file of letters and numbers that, with your agreement, we put on your computer. The cookies we use are primarily analytical cookies that aid us in improving both our Web site and your experience by tracking which areas and features of our Web site are popular, making the Web site easier to navigate, to count visits, and to allow a registered user to remain signed in to his/her user profile throughout a visit. We may also use cookies placed on our Web site by third parties acting on our behalf.

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to prevent this. If you disable cookies, your ability to use some features of the Web site may be limited.

Google Analytics cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our Web site. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve the Web site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the Web site, from where visitors have come to the Web site, and the pages they visited. To opt-out of these cookies, visit [Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Opens in a separate window"). To delete these and any other cookies that are already on your computer, you can also refer to the help and support areas on your Internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

###  Use of Collected Information 

Information about Web site use patterns will be utilized by the Internet Strategies team and other appropriate Northwestern Memorial staff to modify and enhance the Web site. Identifying individual information such as name, e-mail and address will be used only as requested by the visitor. If a visitor submits identifying information, only appropriate Northwestern Memorial staff will be involved in implementing the requested activity. Except as otherwise stated, we may use your information to improve the content of our site, to customize the site to your preferences and to communicate information to you for our marketing and research purposes.

###  Consumer Choices 

Personal information is only collected when a request for service as been issued. Users have the option of asking that personal information be removed from our site once the service has been completed and may end any subscription or request for information by submitting a cancellation request email to Internet Strategies at [webmaster@nmh.org](mailto:webmaster@nmh.org). If Web site users do not wish to have any "cookies" attached to their browser, they may disable cookies through their browser or Internet service company.

###  E-mail Security 

The Northwestern Memorial Web site offers opportunities to communicate with some Northwestern programs by e-mail. Because normal e-mail is not encrypted, the possibility exists that unauthorized individuals may intercept e-mail messages with Northwestern Memorial. Northwestern Memorial is not responsible for privacy of e-mail messages except those stored in our system.

Northwestern Memorial would never ask for personal information such as social security numbers or bank account information through email communications. Should you ever receive such a request, you should contact the Internet Crime Complaint Center, which is a partnership between the FBI and the National White Collar Crime Center.

###  Links 

Northwestern Memorial has contracted with Krames StayWell for access to health information. Users are encouraged to review the privacy policy of Krames StayWell, as Northwestern Memorial is not responsible for the privacy policies or procedures of other sites.

###  Notification of Changes 

Northwestern Memorial has the right to make changes to the Web site privacy statement. Any changes shall be effective on the date posted.
